Guide to the John Lowenthal Papers TAM.190
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Series I: Alger Hiss Research Files, 1934-2003
  - Pilpel, Harriet: Correspondence, May 14, 1974; cuid8375 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Pressman, Lee: Re: Hiss, 1949, 1969, 1977-1994; cuid8376 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Rabinowitz, Victor: Re: Hiss, undated, 1983, 1999; cuid8377 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Raushenbush, Stephen: Correspondence, 1934-1935; cuid8378 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Reuben, William A.: Hiss-Reuben FOIA Suit, 1974-1975, 1980, 1984-1985; cuid8379 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Reuben, William A.: Re: Allen Weinstein, 1992; cuid8380 (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Rosen, William, 1948-1949; cuid8381 (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Ruben, Albert: Correspondence, Sep 25, 2001; cuid8382 (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - Russian/Soviet Archives: Re: Hiss, undated, 1991-1992; cuid8383 (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - Salant, Stephen: Re: FBI's Counter Intelligence Programs, 1959-1960; cuid8384 (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - Salant, Stephen: Re: "Pumpkin Papers", undated, 1974-1975; cuid8385 (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - Sayre, Francis B.: Correspondence, Jan 15, 1949; cuid8386 (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - Schroeter, Leonard: Correspondence, Apr 11, 1975; cuid8387 (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - Shattuck, John H.: American Civil Liberties Union, Nov 21, 1973; cuid8388 (Box 4, Folder 45)
  - Shepherd, Peter: Correspondence, 1998-1999; cuid8389 (Box 4, Folder 46)
  - Solow, Robert: Re: FBI Interview, Jan 28, 1976; cuid8390 (Box 4, Folder 47)
  - Sproul, Kathleen: Correspondence, Apr 29, 1962; cuid8391 (Box 4, Folder 48)
  - Stevenson, Matthew: Re: "Ales", undated, 1987, 1995-2002; cuid8392 (Box 4, Folder 49)
  - Stossel, Frederic: Correspondence, May 2, 1973; cuid8393 (Box 4, Folder 50)
  - Tanenhaus, Sam, 1989-1993, 1998-2001; cuid8394 (Box 4, Folder 51)
  - Thron, C. Davis: Correspondence, 1974, 1994; cuid8395 (Box 4, Folder 52)
  - Toledano, Ralph de, 1950, 1957, 1977-1990; cuid8396 (Box 4, Folder 53)
  - Trials of Alger Hiss: Interviews, Alger Hiss (pp.1-70) (Note: R-7771C/21 Begins Here), Nov 9, 1976, Mar 7, 1978-Mar 8, 1978; cuid8397 (Box 4, Folder 54)
  - Trials of Alger Hiss: Interviews, Alger Hiss (pp.71-169), Nov 10, 1976; cuid8398 (Box 4, Folder 55)
  - Trials of Alger Hiss: Interviews, Alger Hiss (pp.170-252), Jan 22, 1977; cuid8399 (Box 4, Folder 56)
  - Trials of Alger Hiss: Interviews, Alger Hiss (pp. 253-337), Jan 22, 1977; cuid8400 (Box 4, Folder 57)
  - Trials of Alger Hiss: Interviews, Nathan Witt (pp. 338-400), Jan 5, 1977; cuid8401 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Trials of Alger Hiss: Interviews, Ralph de Toledano (pp. 401-448), Apr 6, 1977; cuid8402 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Trials of Alger Hiss: Interviews, John Francis Cronin and Mr. and Mrs. Donald Hiss (pp. 449-510), undated, Apr 8, 1977; cuid8403 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Trials of Alger Hiss: Interviews, Mike, Pat and Raymond Catlett (pp. 511-541), Apr 8, 1977; cuid8404 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Trials of Alger Hiss: Interviews, Ramos Feehan, Harold Rosenwald and Mr. Doyle (pp. 542-652), Apr 26, 1977-Apr 27, 1977; cuid8405 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Trials of Alger Hiss: Interviews, Edward Murtagh, Malcolm Crowley, Isaac Don Levine and David Zablodowsky (pp 653-652a), May 13, 1977; cuid8406 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Trials of Alger Hiss: Interviews, Robert Stripling and Congressman Herbert (pp. 653a-764), undated; cuid8407 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Trials of Alger Hiss: Interviews, Vincent Reno and Sam Krieger (pp. 765-859), Aug 15, 1977; cuid8408 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Trials of Alger Hiss: Interviews, Harold Shapero and Ordman Clubb (pp. 860-981), Sep 7, 1977, Sep 15, 1977; cuid8409 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Trials of Alger Hiss: Interviews, Margaret Halsey and Alger Hiss, Gussie Feinstein (pp. 982-1139/39), Nov 17, 1977; cuid8410 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Trials of Alger Hiss: Interviews, Vincent Shaw (pp. 1113-1164), Mar 18, 1978; cuid8411 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Turner, Catherine: Correspondence, 1993-1994; cuid8412 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - University of Texas at Austin, School of Law: Re: Alger Hiss, 1970-1971; cuid8413 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Van Doren, Mark: (Includes Whittaker Chambers Correspondence), 1926, 1948-1949; cuid8414 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Vassiliev, Alexander: Re: Court Case, 1999-2001; cuid8415 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Vassiliev, Alexander: Re: Court Case, Jan 2002-Apr 2002; cuid8416 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Vassiliev, Alexander: Re: Court Case, May 2002-Oct 2002; cuid8417 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Venona: Documents, 1950-1956; cuid8418 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Venona: Re: "Ales", 1956, 1996, 1999; cuid8419 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Volkogonov, Dmitri, undated, 1992-1994; cuid8420 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Vorontsov, Yuri: Re: Hiss, 1992-1993; cuid8421 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Weinstein, Allen: Re: Perjury, 1978; cuid8422 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Weissberger, L. Arnold: Re: Hiss, 1965-1978; cuid8423 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Werchen, Raymond: Writings Re: Hiss, 1973, 1976; cuid8424 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Weyl, Nathaniel, undated, 1952; cuid8425 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Whitman, Alden, 1974-1975; cuid8426 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Zeligs, Meyer: Correspondence, 1962-1965, 1977-1978; cuid8427 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Zeligs, Meyer: Re: Friendship and Fratricide, undated, 1963-1970; cuid8428 (Box 5, Folder 28)
- Series II: Subject Files, 1942-2003
  - Abt, John J., 1953, 1958, 1977; cuid8429 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Adams,: "Nothing to Fear but Fear Itself," Typescript (British Broadcasting Service), undated; cuid8430 (Box 6, Folder 1a)
  - Adler, Mortimer: Correspondence, Nov 1, 1976-Dec 1, 1976; cuid8431 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Aldrich, Richard: Re: The Haunted Wood, May 1, 2003; cuid8432 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - The Alger Hiss Case in America and Russia (JL): Typescript, 1993; cuid8433 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Alger Hiss: The Perfect Victim: Correspondence and Typescript, 2003; cuid8434 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Alger Hiss and William A. Reuben v. U.S. Department of Justice et al., Sep 2, 1981; cuid8435 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Allen, George: Re: J. Edgar Hoover, Homosexuality, 1946, 1987; cuid8436 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Andrew, Christophe, 1999-2001; cuid8437 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Association of American Indian Affairs: Memorandum, Jun 4, 1984; cuid8438 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Bannerman, Robert L.: Handwritten Notes, re:, Mar 30, 1977; cuid8439 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Barksdale, Calvert: Seaver Books, re: Coram Nobis Manuscript, 1987; cuid8440 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Bogert, Carroll, 1994; cuid8441 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Bonin, Richard: 60 Minutes, 1992; cuid8442 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Book Two: Unsigned Typescript, undated; cuid8443 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Botstein, Leon, 1981, 1992-1993; cuid8444 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Boughton, James: Articles and Correspondence, 2000-2001; cuid8445 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Brent, Jonathan: Yale University Press, 1992-1993; cuid8446 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Breyer, Henry W. Jr.: Handwritten Notes, re:, 1950; cuid8447 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Brick, Richard: Correspondence, undated, 1984-1985; cuid8448 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Brick, Richard: Silo Cinema, 1976-1981, 1992; cuid8449 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Brown, William Adams: Correspondence, Feb 6, 1950; cuid8450 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Bush, Flora Wilhelm: "A Discussion of the Case of Alger Hiss", 1979; cuid8451 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Cammer, Harold I.: Letter to the Editor re: Lionel Trilling/Chambers, Apr 7, 1975; cuid8452 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Cantwell, Robert, 1973, 1977-1978; cuid8453 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Carlsen, Carl E.: Correspondence, 1975, 1980; cuid8454 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Cass, Stewart: Correspondence, 2003; cuid8455 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Chaly, Ingeborg: "Rhetorical Discretion and Legal Constraints in Jury Instructions: A Comparative Analysis of the Two Charges to the Jury in the Alger Hiss Perjury Trials", 1981; cuid8456 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Chamberlain, John: Handwritten Notes, re:, Apr 21, 1977; cuid8457 (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Chambers, John: Handwritten Notes, re:, Jan 19, 1977; cuid8458 (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Chambers, Whittaker: Homosexuality, 1948-1950, 1974-1977, 1999; cuid8459 (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - Chambers, Whittaker: Investigation of, Nov 1948; cuid8460 (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - Chambers, Whittaker: Notes for Book, re:, Sep 6, 1999; cuid8461 (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - Chambers, Whittaker: Notes re: Break with Communist Party, Feb 13, 1994; cuid8462 (Box 6, Folder 33)
  - Chambers, Whittaker: Writings in The Saturday Evening Post, 1952; cuid8463 (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - Chandler, Tertius: Correspondence, 1976; cuid8464 (Box 6, Folder 35)
  - Clark, Blair: The Nation, Correspondence, 1976; cuid8465 (Box 6, Folder 36)
  - Clubb, Oliver Edmund, 1977-1978, 1989; cuid8466 (Box 6, Folder 37)
  - Cold War International History Project: "The Hiss Case and Soviet Archives," Typescript (drafts), Dec 17, 1993-Mar 16, 1994; cuid8467 (Box 6, Folder 38)
  - Cold War International History Project: "The Hiss Case and Soviet Archives," Typescript (drafts), Mar 18, 1994-Apr 25, 1994; cuid8468 (Box 6, Folder 39)
  - Commentary: Correspondence, 1990-1993; cuid8469 (Box 6, Folder 40)
  - Committee on Un-American Activities, U.S. House of Representatives (HUAC): Pamphlets, 1948; cuid8470 (Box 6, Folder 41)
  - Communist Party, U.S.A., 1946-1951; cuid8471 (Box 6, Folder 42)
  - Compton, James: "Anti-Communism in American Life Since the Second World War" and Correspondence, 1973, 1993; cuid8472 (Box 6, Folder 43)
  - Connelley, Earl J: Affidavit, Mar 12, 1952; cuid8473 (Box 6, Folder 44)
  - Correspondence: General, undated, 1962-1963, 1970-1999; cuid8474 (Box 6, Folder 45)
  - Correspondence: Re: John Earl Haynes, 2000-2001; cuid8475 (Box 6, Folder 46)
  - Correspondence: Re: William A. Reuben's Writings, 1995-1997; cuid8476 (Box 6, Folder 47)
  - Counterattack, 1948; cuid8477 (Box 6, Folder 48)
  - Cowley, Michael: Clippings and Correspondence, 1977-1981; cuid8478 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Craig, Bruce: "A Matter of Espionage: Alger Hiss, Harry Dexter White and Igor Gouzenko-The Canadian Connection Reassessed," Typescript, 2000; cuid8479 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Craig, Bruce: Re: Opening Hiss Grand Jury Records, 1996-1999; cuid8480 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Craig, Bruce: Writings, undated, 1990, 1996; cuid8481 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Cronin, John F., 1940s, 1968-1980, 1994; cuid8482 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Cross, Claude B.: "'The Assistance of Counsel for His Defense': Is This Becoming a Meaningless Guarantee?" American Bar Association Journal, Dec 1952; cuid8483 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Currie, Laughlin, 1940-1959, 2002; cuid8484 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Davies, John: Correspondence, Jun 2, 1942; cuid8485 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Davis, John F.: Handwritten Notes, re:, Dec 30, 1976; cuid8486 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Dean, John, 1974-1977; cuid8487 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Douglas, William O., 1976, 2003; cuid8488 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Doyle, Jerome, 1948, 1977-1978, 1999; cuid8489 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - The Dreyfus Case and the Hiss Case: Points of Similarity and Points of Difference, Typescript, undated; cuid8490 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Eddy, George: Chambers-Hiss, Typescript, 1959-1960; cuid8491 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Einstein, Albert: Handwritten Notes, re:, 1984-1988; cuid8492 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Elsten, David: Hiss/Venona Documentary, 2000-2001; cuid8493 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Elsten, David: Thames Television, Inc., 1978-1983; cuid8494 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Espionage Law: Handwritten Notes, re:, undated, 1997; cuid8495 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - The Eye of a Bird: Play re: Hiss, undated; cuid8496 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - FBI: FOIA Request re: John Lowenthal, 1978; cuid8497 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Field, Noel: Article and Handwritten Notes, Re:, 1993-1994, 2000-2002; cuid8498 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Footnote on a Historic Case: In Re: Alger Hiss, No. 78 Civ. 3433 (JL) (Nation Institute), 1983; cuid8499 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Gates, John: Handwritten Notes, re:, 1977-1978; cuid8500 (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Glazer, Nathan: The National Interest, 1993; cuid8501 (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Global American Television, Inc.: Correspondence, 1993; cuid8502 (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - Gordievsky, Oleg A.: Article and Clippings, re:, 1990, 1995; cuid8503 (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - Gorizontov, Leonid: East European Scientific and Information Agency, undated, 1992; cuid8504 (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - Griffin, Kevin W.: Correspondence and Handwritten Notes, re:, 1978; cuid8505 (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - Gwynn, Beatrice: Correspondence, 1976, 1997; cuid8506 (Box 7, Folder 29)
  - Gwynn, Beatrice: "The Discrepancies in the Evidence," Typescript, undated; cuid8507 (Box 7, Folder 30)
  - Gwynn, Beatrice: Translation of Augusto Marcelli's Article in Paese Sera re: Hiss' Visit to Italy, Sep 27, 1970; cuid8508 (Box 7, Folder 31)
  - Halperin, Morton: Re: Herbert Hoover, Official and Confidential Files, 1975-1976; cuid8509 (Box 7, Folder 32)
  - Halperin, Morton: Re: Wiretapping, 1976; cuid8510 (Box 7, Folder 33)
  - Hamilton, James: Correspondence, 1979, 1982, 1999-2003; cuid8511 (Box 7, Folder 34)
  - Hamilton, James: Writings, undated, 1981, 1993-1999; cuid8512 (Box 7, Folder 35)
  - Handwritten Notes: Re: Hiss, 1950-1979, 1999; cuid8513 (Box 7, Folder 36)
  - Haury, Agnese Nelms (formerly Agnese Nelms Lindley and Agnese Nelms Lockwood): Correspondence and Memoranda, 1974-1981, 1992-2001; cuid8514 (Box 7, Folder 37)
  - Heller, Howard: Correspondence, 1984; cuid8515 (Box 7, Folder 38)
  - Heller, Howard: "The Hiss Case Hoax," Typescript (I), undated; cuid8516 (Box 7, Folder 39)
  - Heller, Howard: "The Hiss Case Hoax," Typescript (II), undated; cuid8517 (Box 7, Folder 40)
  - Heller, Howard: "The Hiss Case Hoax," Typescript (III), undated; cuid8518 (Box 7, Folder 41)
  - Heller, Howard: "The Hiss Case Hoax," Typescript (IV), undated; cuid8519 (Box 7, Folder 42)
  - Hiss, Alger: Re: "Ales"/Mars, Jan 2, 1949; cuid8520 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Hiss, Alger: Clippings, 1948-1950; cuid8521 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Hiss, Alger: Clippings, 1961-1966; cuid8522 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Hiss, Alger: Clippings, 1967-1974; cuid8523 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Hiss, Alger: Clippings, 1975-1977; cuid8524 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Hiss, Alger: Clippings, 1978, 1980; cuid8525 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Hiss, Alger: Clippings, 1981-1983; cuid8526 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Hiss, Alger: Freedom of Information Act (FOIA) Files I, 1940s; cuid8527 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Hiss, Alger: FOIA II, 1940s; cuid8528 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Hiss, Alger: FOIA III, 1940s; cuid8529 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Hiss, Alger: FBI Report, 1941-1942, 1948; cuid8530 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Hiss, Alger: Law Talk, undated; cuid8531 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Hiss, Alger: McCarthy Era, Notes re:, 1980s; cuid8532 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Hiss, Alger: Nye Committee, Hiss Questions Bernard Baruch, 1990s; cuid8533 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Hiss, Alger: Obituaries, Nov 16, 1996-Nov 19, 1996; cuid8534 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Hiss, Alger: Re: Franklin Delano Roosevelt, 1980s; cuid8535 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Hiss, Alger: Yalta Conference, Articles re:, undated, Nov 1955; cuid8536 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Hiss Case: Alger Hiss v. U.S.A., 1950; cuid8537 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Hiss Case: Alger Hiss v. U.S.A., 1952; cuid8538 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Hiss Case: Alger Hiss v. Whittaker Chambers, In the U.S. District Court for the District of Maryland Civil No. 4176, Deposition of Whittaker Chambers, Direct (pp. 1-209), Nov 4, 1948; cuid8539 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Hiss Case: Alger Hiss v. Whittaker Chambers, In the U.S. District Court for the District of Maryland Civil No. 4176, Deposition of Whittaker Chambers, Direct (pp. 210-440)), Nov 5, 1948; cuid8540 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Hiss Case: Alger Hiss v. Whittaker Chambers, In the U.S. District Court for the District of Maryland Civil No. 4176, Deposition of Mrs. Esther Chambers, Direct (pp. 441-640), Nov 17, 1948; cuid8541 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Hiss Case: Alger Hiss v. Whittaker Chambers, In the U.S. District Court for the District of Maryland Civil No. 4176, Deposition of Mrs. Esther Chambers, Direct (pp. 641-715), Nov 17, 1948; cuid8542 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Hiss Case: Alger Hiss v. Whittaker Chambers, In the U.S. District Court for the District of Maryland Civil No. 4176, Deposition of Whittaker Chambers, Direct (pp. 716-829), Nov 17, 1948; cuid8543 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Hiss Case: Alger Hiss v. Whittaker Chambers, In the U.S. District Court for the District of Maryland Civil No. 4176, Deposition of Whittaker Chambers, Direct (pp. 830-1061), Nov 17, 1948; cuid8544 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Hiss Case: Alger Hiss v. Whittaker Chambers, In the U.S. District Court for the District of Maryland Civil No. 4176, Deposition of Whittaker Chambers, Direct (pp. 1062-1290), Feb 18, 1949; cuid8545 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Hiss Case: Alger Hiss v. Whittaker Chambers, In the U.S. District Court for the District of Maryland Civil No. 4176, Deposition of Whittaker Chambers, (pp. 1291-1382), Mar 25, 1949; cuid8546 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Hiss Case: Alger Hiss, Richard Strasburger and Besse Brown Strasberger v. Robert E. Hampton et al., 1972; cuid8547 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Hiss Case: Baltimore Depositions, Notes, 1976, 1993-1994; cuid8548 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Hiss Case: Baltimore Exhibits (Lowenthal reference file, mostly defense materials: memos, correspondence, background on Woodstock typewriter, etc.), 1948-1949, 1962-1976; cuid8549 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Hiss Case: Bykov, Boris, 1945, 1949, 2003; cuid8550 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Hiss Case: Catlett, Mike and Pat, 1949, 1977-1978; cuid8551 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Hiss Case: Chambers, Whittaker and Esther, undated, 1945-1952; cuid8552 (Box 10, Folder 4a)
  - Hiss Case: Character Witnesses, Individuals and Organizations, 1948; cuid8553 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Hiss Case: Collins, Henry, 1948, 1951; cuid8554 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Hiss Case: Davis, John, 1948-1949; cuid8555 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Hiss Case: "Die Deutsche Regierung...": Aide-Memoire, on 1930s Trade (in German; photostat; labeled 611.6231/987), Undated; cuid8556 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Hiss Case: Dulles, John Foster, Jul 1, 1949; cuid8557 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Hiss Case: Fearon, Edwin, 1949; cuid8558 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Hiss Case: FBI Memos, 1948-1949, 1956, 1963-1978; cuid8559 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Hiss Case: Government Exhibits (List and misc. copies, 1st and 2nd trials?), undated, 1938-1949; cuid8560 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Hiss Case: Inslerman, Felix, Jan 21, 1949; cuid8561 (Box 10, Folder 12a)
  - Hiss Case: In the Matter of Alger Hiss, Appendix to the Brief for the Petitioner, 1974-1975; cuid8562 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Hiss Case: In the Matter of Alger Hiss, Brief for the Petitioner, undated; cuid8563 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Hiss Case: In the Matter of Alger Hiss, Brief of the Bar Counsel, May 1975; cuid8564 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Hiss Case: In Re: Alger Hiss, Brief for Petitioner-Appellant, Nov 30, 1982; cuid8565 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Hiss Case: In Re: Alger Hiss, Brief for Respondent-Appellee, USA, Jul 15, 1982; cuid8566 (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Hiss Case: In Re: Alger Hiss, Brief for the United States in Opposition, Oct 1983; cuid8567 (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Hiss Case: In Re: Alger Hiss, Memorandum in Support of Petitioner's Motion to Grant Writ of Coram Nobis, Jul 8, 1980; cuid8568 (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Hiss Case: In Re: Alger Hiss, Memorandum of Law in Opposition to Petitioner's Application for a Writ of Error Coram Nobis, Jul 27, 1978; cuid8569 (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - Hiss Case: In Re: Alger Hiss, Memorandum of Law in Opposition to Petitioner's Application for a Writ of Error Coram Nobis and to Petitioner's Application for an Evidentiary Hearing and Discovery, Nov 20, 1979; cuid8570 (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - Hiss Case: In Re: Alger Hiss, Opinion of Richard Owen, Jul 15, 1982; cuid8571 (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - Hiss Case: In Re: Alger Hiss, Petition for Reargument and Rehearing En Banc, Feb 24, 1983; cuid8572 (Box 10, Folder 23)
  - Hiss Case: In Re: Alger Hiss, Petition for Writ of Certiorari to the U.S. Court of Appeals for the Second Circuit, Jun 17, 1983; cuid8573 (Box 10, Folder 24)
  - Hiss Case: In Re: Alger Hiss, Petition for Writ of Error Coram Nobis, Jul 27, 1978; cuid8574 (Box 10, Folder 25)
  - Hiss Case: In Re: Alger Hiss, Reply Brief for Petitioner-Appellant, Feb 9, 1983; cuid8575 (Box 10, Folder 26)
  - Hiss Case: In Re: Alger Hiss, Reply Brief in Support of Petition for a Writ of Certiorari, Sep 30, 1983; cuid8576 (Box 10, Folder 27)
  - Hiss Case: Investigators, 1949-1950; cuid8577 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Hiss Case: Jurors, 1949, 1977-1978; cuid8578 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Hiss Case: Lane, Chester, 1950; cuid8579 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Hiss Case: New England Spectrochemical Laboratories, 1956; cuid8580 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Hiss Case: Oral Testimonies, Notes, 1940s, 1970s; cuid8581 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Hiss Case: Pigman, Ward, 1948-1949; cuid8582 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Hiss Case: Reinstatement to Massachusetts State Bar, Amicus Curia Brief of the Boston Bar Association, May 7, 1975; cuid8583 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Hiss Case: Reinstatement to Massachusetts State Bar, Application, Jan 7, 1975; cuid8584 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Hiss Case: Reinstatement to Massachusetts State Bar, On Report by a Justice of the Supreme Court for Suffolk County, [1975]; cuid8585 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Hiss Case: Russian Archives, 1992; cuid8586 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Hiss Case: Schmahl, Horace, undated, 1941-1952, 1971-1975; cuid8587 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Hiss Case: Time, Life, Fortune, Editors, 1930-1959; cuid8588 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Hiss Case: U.S.A. v. Alger Hiss, Appeal from a Judgment of the District Court for the Southern District of New York, Dec 7, 1950; cuid8589 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Hiss Case: U.S.A. v. Alger Hiss, Brief for Appellant, undated; cuid8590 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Hiss Case: U.S.A. v. Alger Hiss, Memorandum in Support of Defendant's Motion for a New Trial Under Rule 33 on the Ground of Newly Discovered Evidence, 1952; cuid8591 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Hiss Case: U.S.A. v. Alger Hiss, On Appeal, Appellant's Brief, Nov 1952; cuid8592 (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Hiss Case: U.S.A. v. Alger Hiss, On Appeal, Appendix to Appellant's Brief, Jul 22, 1952; cuid8593 (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Hiss Case: U.S.A. v. Alger Hiss, On Appeal, Consolidated Index of Record, undated; cuid8594 (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - Hiss Case: U.S.A. v. Alger Hiss, On Appeal, Petition for Rehearing, undated; cuid8595 (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - Hiss Case: U.S.A. v. Alger Hiss, On Appeal, Transcript of Record, Volume I, Jan 25, 1950; cuid8596 (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - Hiss Case: U.S.A. v. Alger Hiss, On Appeal, Transcript of Record, Volume II, Jan 25, 1950; cuid8597 (Box 11, Folder 21)
  - Hiss Case: U.S.A. v. Alger Hiss, On Appeal, Transcript of Record, Volume III, Jan 25, 1950; cuid8598 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Hiss Case: U.S.A. v. Alger Hiss, On Appeal, Transcript of Record, Volume IV, Jan 25, 1950; cuid8599 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Hiss Case: U.S.A. v. Alger Hiss, On Appeal, Transcript of Record, Volume V, Jan 25, 1950; cuid8600 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Hiss Case: U.S.A. v. Alger Hiss, On Appeal, Transcript of Record, Volume VI, Jan 25, 1950; cuid8601 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Hiss Case: U.S.A. v. Alger Hiss, On Appeal, Transcript of Record, Volume VII, Jan 25, 1950; cuid8602 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Hiss Case: U.S.A. v. Alger Hiss, On Appeal, Transcript of Record, Volume VIII, Jan 25, 1950; cuid8603 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Hiss Case: U.S.A. v. Alger Hiss, On Appeal, Transcript of Record, Volume IX, Jan 25, 1950; cuid8604 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Hiss Case: U.S.A. v. Alger Hiss, On Appeal, Transcript of Record, Volume X, Jan 25, 1950; cuid8605 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Hiss Case: U.S.A. v. Alger Hiss, Second Supplemental Affidavit, 1952; cuid8606 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Hiss Case: U.S.A. v. Alger Hiss, Stenographer's Minutes, May 31, 1949; cuid8607 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Hiss Case: U.S.A. v. Alger Hiss, Stenographer's Minutes, Jun 6, 1949; cuid8608 (Box 13, Folder 2)